Nathan's Gouri here with a draft recap
edition of the 2-minute drill brought to
you by University Hospitals. The 2026
NFL draft is in the books and your
Cleveland Browns selected 10 players in
that draft, eight on offense, two on
defense, and many people, many draft
pundits around the NFL world are buzzing
about this draft. In fact, they have
received the top grade in terms of
having the best draft by many of these
people. Of course, Todd Monken, the head
coach of the Browns, will tell you, "Ham
now grades right now, that's silly." But
in terms of the Browns' ability to
execute on their plan, this was a huge
success. Browns ended up getting four
players that they thought were
first-round picks, starting with number
nine, Spencer Fano, the tackle out of
Utah, the Browns' top-rated offensive
lineman and offensive tackle in this
draft. Now, the Browns originally picked
at six, they were able to move back to
number nine, [music]
they picked up an extra third-round pick
for that, and were able to still get the
guy they wanted. Later at pick number 24
in the first round, the Browns would
take wide receiver Casey Conceição, and
then at number 39 to kick off the second
round, they would take wide receiver
Denzel Boston. So, Conceição, a great
separator, elusive after the catch,
home-run hitter, and also the best punt
returner in the SEC. The guy won the
Paul Hornung Award as the most versatile
player in college football last year,
and you pair him with the 6'4" Denzel
Boston. Those two combined for 52
touchdowns in college. They know how to
put the football into the end zone, and
that's something I think the Cleveland
Browns fans are going to be very excited
to see going forward. Both of them just
good receivers, different body types,
different skill sets. And that double-up
theme, well, guess what? Going back to
Spencer Fano, the Browns in the third
round also picked up Austin Barber, 6'7"
tackle out of Florida, former basketball
player, plays with a mean streak, also
might have some guard potential. And
then they stayed on the offensive line
in the fifth round as they got center
Parker Brailsford from Alabama. A little
bit of an undersized center, but one of
the strongest players in this draft, and
also the fastest lineman in this draft
in terms of the 10-yard split, 1.7
seconds. They love his movement skills,
and it's reminiscent Think about Todd
Monken George Warhop [music] did in
Baltimore with Tyler Linderbaum, an
undersized center who just was the
highest-paid center in the NFL. So,
three players on the offensive line,
those two receivers that I mentioned for
you as well, and then rounding out on
the offensive side, the Browns took two
tight ends, Joe Royer out of Cincinnati.
Royer once had 50 receptions in a season
down at Cincinnati, breaking Travis
Kelce's record of 45 receptions, the
most by a tight end at that point in
Cincinnati history. And then in the
final round, they added Carson Ryan, a
tight end from BYU, who they think maybe
could be not only kind of a tight end,
but a little bit of an H-back fullback
as well here in this Todd Monken
offense. Quarterback Taylen Green, 6'6",
230 from Arkansas, one of the most
explosive athletes in this draft, in
fact, the most explosive quarterback
athlete profile that they have ever seen
since they started doing that RAS,
relative athletic score. He can throw it
a mile, he can run it, he is big, but he
needs some refinement. Turnovers
obviously a problem in Arkansas, but you
talk about a ball of clay, this is a
great ball of clay, and now the Browns'
staff's going to have to mold it. So,
those are the eight guys on offense
ultimately. Now, on the other side of
the ball, you got to go back to the
second round as Andrew Berry masterfully
traded back up into the second round
with one of those third-round picks.
Remember, they made that trade with Fano
to pick up an extra one, they used one
of those to get back there in the second
round, and they get Emmanuel McNeil out
of Warren from Toledo, 6'4", great size.
Coach Bonda, our safeties coach, was
writing notes, posted notes with his
name in a heart circled in it. Check it
out at clevelandbrowns.com, I'm not
making that up. He loved him, the Browns
get him. That gives them four guys that
they really think were first-rounders
[music] in this draft. And then the
Browns rounded out things on the
defensive side by getting Justin
Jefferson, the linebacker from Alabama.
And this guy is a dog, fought his way
from [music] junior college to Alabama
to becoming a starter, and now on the
Browns. A little bit of an undersized
linebacker, but he can absolutely run,
and he can hit. So, that's the draft
recap there for the Browns. Ultimately,
they get 10 players, eight on offense,
two on defense. Again, pundits are
saying that this is one of the best
drafts they've seen. The execution by
Andrew Berry and his team was
phenomenal. Now, we got to turn these
theoreticals right into actual players.
We're going to get to see that at the
rookie mini-camp here in a couple of
weeks. For a complete breakdown of the
Browns' draft and all things Cleveland
Browns, head to clevelandbrowns.com and
the Browns mobile app. This has been the
draft recap edition of the 2-minute
drill brought to you by University
Hospitals.